The following concept is one that works both for regression and classification.
接下来要学习的这个概念适用于回归和分类
So in this video, we'll explain it using a classification problem.
在这个视频里 我会用一个分类场景来解释这个新概念
But as you will see, all the arguments here work with regression algorithms as well.
但是你会发现 所有参数值也适用于回归算法
The concept is called regularization,
这个概念叫做正则化
it's a very useful technique to improve our models and make sure they don't over fit.
这是改善我们模型 确保不会过度拟合的有效技巧
So let's look at some data, here's the data,
那么我们来看一下这些数据 这是一些数据
and let's make two copies of it,
已经备份了
and let's look at two models that classify this data.
我们看一下分类数据的两个模型
The first one is a line and the second one is a higher degree polynomial curve.
第一个是一条直线 第二个是高次多项式
So, the question is which one is better?
那么问题是 哪个更好呢？
Well, they both have their pros and cons, right?
两种方法是不是各有利弊？
The one on the left makes a couple of mistakes.
左侧这个存在各种错误
As you can see, there is a red point and
可以看到 有一个红点和
a blue point in the wrong sides but it is much simpler.
蓝点都在错误位置 但是这种方法更加简单
The one on the right makes zero mistakes but it's actually a bit more complicated.
右侧这个没有任何错误 但实际上有点更加复杂
So let's say we want the one on the left because the one on
那么如果我们想要左侧这个
the right over fits and it just doesn't generalize well.
因为右侧这个过度拟合 并且不太好泛化
So the problem is that when we train the model,
问题在于当我们训练模型时
the one on the right will appear more likely and the reason is the following.
右侧这个更可能出现 原因如下
When we're training the model,
当我们训练模型时
the model takes an error and minimizes it.
模型得到误差 并进行最小化
So, the model on the left has a small error since it own
左侧这个误差较小
misclassifies two points but it's an error nonetheless.
虽然只有两个点错了 但也是错了
The model in the right has a really small error since it
右侧这个的误差更小
does not misclassifies any of the points.
因为没有分类错误
So, if we train a model to minimize error,
当我们训练模型来最小化误差时
it will build a boundary like the one on the right, not the one on the left.
模型会像右边这个一样建立边界 而不会遵循左边这个
So the question is, how do we pick the one in the left? Well, here's an idea.
那么我们如何得到左侧的呢？答案是这样的
Let's look at the equation and let's say the equation of the line on the left is
来看看等式 比如左边的直线等式是
something like 3x_1 plus 4x_2 plus five equals zero.
3X1 + 4X2 + 5 = 0
The equation of the polynomial is something more complex with
多元方程式可能更加复杂 包括高次项 例如
high degree terms like x_1 squared x_1 x_2 x_2 cube, et cetera.
X1 的平方或 X1 乘以 X2 或者 X1 的三次方等
If we look at the equation in the left,
如果我们观察左边的多项式
it's much simpler than the equation on the right.
这个要比右侧的更加简单
In particular, there are less coefficients, only three,
系数更少 只有 3 4 5
four, five whereas the right one has many more.
而右边的要多很多
So, if we find a way to in commend the error by some function of these numbers,
因此 如果我们能够通过关于这些数字的某个函数来表达这种误差
that would be very helpful because in some way
那将非常有用 因为在某种程度上
the complexity of the model will be added into the error.
模型的复杂性将体现在这个函数中
So a complex model will have a larger error and then a simple model.
所以一个复杂模型相较于简单模型将得到更大的误差
So, let's do that and I'll show you the details later but the idea is that
我们来做一下 随后我会向你展示细节 但总体想法是
we take this three and four and notice that we're forgetting about the constant term,
我们使用这里的 3 和 4 注意我们这里忽略了常数项
and there's a reason for that.
这是有原因的
But if we take this three and four and say add them to the error,
如果我们用 3 和 4 并加到误差中
we get a slightly bigger error.
们得到稍大一些的误差
But what if we take all these coefficients and add them to the error here,
但是如果我们拿 2 2 4 -3 6 4  并全部加到误差中
now we get a huge error.
会得到很大的误差
Now, we can see that the modeling the left is better
现在我们看到左侧模型更好一些
because it has a smaller combined error, so again,
因为它的总体误差更小 所以 我们要做的是
what we did is we took the complexity in the model into account,
在计算误差时考虑模型的复杂性
when we calculated the error and in that way,
从这个角度来说
a simpler model has an edge over the complicated model.
简单的模型比复杂的模型更胜一筹
Simpler models have a tendency to generalize better so, that's what we want.
简单的模型也可以容易泛化 而这也符合我们的目标
So now, let me be more detailed on how to take
现在 我来讲解如何在计算误差时
the complexity of a model and turn into part of the error.
考虑模型的复杂性
In summary, will take this highlighted coefficients and somehow add them to the error,
简单来说 就是拿这些高亮的系数 并加到误差里
this method is called L1 regularization and it's very simple, here's how it works.
这种方法叫做 L1 正则化 非常简单 我给你看一下
What L1 regularization does,
L1 正则化就是
it takes the coefficient and just adds the absolute values of them to the error.
拿这些系数 并且把它们的绝对值加起来 加到误差里
So in this case, we're adding absolute value
比如在这个例子里   2 的绝对值是 2
of two which is two plus absolute value of minus two,
-2 的绝对值也是 2 等等
which is two again, et cetera and we see that they add to 21.
所有系数绝对值加起来是 21
In the linear case,
在直线例子里
we see that we're adding is the absolute value of three and four which is seven,
我们是拿了 3 和 4 的绝对值相加 也就是 7
so a seven is much less than 21,
7 比 21 要小很多
we can see that the complicated model gives us a much higher error.
所以这就是为什么复杂的模型得出较大的误差
That's L1 regularization and the one is attached to the absolute value.
这就是 L1 正则化 它与绝对值相关
L2 regularization is very similar and what we do
L2 正则化是类似的 我们这里要做的
here is instead of adding the absolute values,
不是得到绝对值
we add the squares of the coefficients.
而是把系数的平方加起来
So for the complicated case,
对于复杂模型例子
we get two squared plus minus two squared,
我们把 2 的平方加 -2 的平方加上 -4 的平方等等
et cetera which gives us 85.
最后得到 85
For the linear case, we get three squared plus four squared which is 25,
在直线的这个例子中 我们将 3 的平方加 4 的平方等于 25
which is much smaller than 85.
这个值远小于 85
So again, we see that the complex model gets punished a lot more than the simple model.
我们再次看到复杂模型将比简单模型受到更多“惩罚”
But now the question is,
但是现在问题是
what if we punish the complicated model too little or what if we punish it too much?
如果我们惩罚复杂模型太少或者太多怎么办？
Maybe some models, like a model to send a rocket to the moon or a medical model,
也许有些模型 比如将火箭发送到月球或医学模型
have very little room for error and we're okay with some complexity,
几乎没有容错的余地 那么我们可以接受一定的复杂性
or maybe other models like a video recommendation model,
而另一些其他模型 如视频推荐
or model recommending potential friends on a social network have more room
或社交网络上的潜在好友推荐则有更多容错空间
for experimenting and need to be simpler and faster to run a big data.
需要模型简单从而更快地处理海量数据
So we're okay with having some error.
因此我们可以接受有一定误差
So it seems that for every case,
似乎对于每一个案例
we have to tune how much we want to punish complexity in each model.
我们必须调整要在多大程度上“惩罚”每个模型的复杂度
This can be fixed with a parameter and this parameter is called lambda.
这个问题可以通过参数 λ 来解决
What we do with lambda,
我们将 λ
is we multiply the complexity part of the error as follows.
乘以误差中的复杂度部分 如下所示
Let's look at the two models again and let's
让我们再看一下这两个模型
remember that the yellow part of the error comes from
记住误差中的黄色部分来自
the misclassified points and the green part comes from the complexity of the model,
被错误分类的点 绿色部分来自模型的复杂度
namely the coefficients in the polynomial.
即多项式中的系数
Let's say, we have a small lambda,
比方说 我们有一个很小的 λ
so we take the green error and multiplied by small lambda which gives us something small.
当我们将绿色部分的误差乘以 λ 后得到的结果也很小
Therefore, the right model still wins because
因此 右边的模型依然更好
the complexity part of the error is small and it won't swing the balance.
因为误差中关于模型复杂度的部分很小并且不会有很大波动
But if we have a large value for lambda,
但是如果我们有一个很大的 λ
then we're multiplying the complexity part of the error by a lot.
那么误差中关于模型复杂度的部分将乘以一个很大的值 而被放大很多
Which punishes the complex model more and then the simple model wins.
这将更大程度地惩罚了复杂模型 因此简单模型获胜
So in summary, this is what happens,
总而言之
if we have a large lambda then we're punishing
如果我们的 λ 值很大
complexity by a large amount and we're picking a simpler model.
那么将对模型复杂度有很大程度的惩罚 我们选择更简单的模型
Whereas if we have a small lambda,
而如果我们有一个小的 λ 值
then we're punishing complexity by a small amount,
那么我们对模型复杂度的惩罚将很小
so we're okay with having more complex models.
因此我们可以选择更复杂的模型
Now the question is, which one to use L1 or L2 regularization?
现在的问题是我们应该使用哪个呢？ L1 还是 L2？
So here's a cheat sheet with some benefits for each one.
这里是每个 L1 和 L2 优点的备忘单
L1 regularization is actually computationally inefficient
所以 L1 正则化实际上有着较低效的计算
even though it seems simpler because it has no squares,
虽然它没有平方 看起来好像更简单
but actually those absolute values are hard to differentiate.
但实际上那些绝对值很难求导
Whereas, an L2 regularization squares have very nice derivatives.
而 L2 正则化的平方具有很漂亮的导数
So, these are easy to deal with computation.
因此这些更容易进行计算处理
The only times where L1 regularization is faster than
L1 正则化比 L2 更快只会发生在
L2 regularization is when the data is sparse.
数据稀疏时
So let's say if you have a thousand columns of data but
假如你有一千列数据
only 10 are relevant and the rest are mostly zeros,
但是只有十列是相关的 其余大多都是零
then L1 is faster,
那么此时 L1 更快
L2 is better for non-sparse outputs which
L2 对于非稀疏的输出更好
is when the data is more equally distributed among the columns.
此时数据在各列之间更均匀地分布
L1 has one huge benefit which is that,
L1 有一个巨大的好处就是
it gives us feature selection.
它给了我们特征选择
So let's say, we have again,
再比如说
data in a thousand columns but really only
我们还是有一千列数据 但是确实只有
10 of them matters and the rest are mostly noise.
十列是有用的而剩下的都是噪音
So, L1 will detect this and will make the relevant columns into zeroes.
L1将检测到这一点 并将那些列设为零
L2 on the other hand won't do this and it just take the columns and treat them similarly.
而 L2 却不会这样做 它只是把所有的列拿来近似地处理它们
So that's it, that's regularization.
就是这样 这就是正则化